http://www.iris.co.uk/cookie-policy

Contact Us | Call us on 0344 2251525
ProductsAccountancy solutionsBy business typeAccountant in PracticeAccountant in BusinessBookkeeperBy business sizeSmallMediumLarge
Payroll managementBy business typeEmployersBureauHealthcare ProviderFeatured productsManaged Payroll ServiceFree PayrollGP PayrollEnterprise Payroll
HR managementBy business typeEmployerHealthcare ProviderBy business sizeSmallMediumLarge
Business accountingBy business typeAccountancy PracticeBookkeeperCharityHealthcare ProviderEducation ProviderBusinessProfessional ServicesMuseums, Venues, HospitalityBy business sizeSmallMediumLarge
Education managementBy organisationMulti Academy TrustFurther EducationSchoolInternational schoolsNurseryClubsLocal AuthoritiesFeatured productsIRIS FinancialsParentMailBioStoreTruancy CallIRIS Looked After CallIRIS PlusPay
SME
SolutionsBy business sizeSmallMediumFeatured productsKashFlow Accounting SoftwareKashFlow PayrollIRIS HR ProfessionalLarge Business SolutionsBy business sizeMediumLargeFeatured productsIRIS Fully Managed PayrollIRIS PayriteIRIS CascadeIRIS FinancialsIRIS HostingIRIS AssetsBiometric Systems and TechnologyBy industryEducationBusinessFeatured productsIdentity ManagementCashless CateringAccess Control SystemsSchool Meal ManagementSchool Meal ReportingResourcesEventsHighlighted EventsIRIS World 2020 Recap Events
We don’t just attend nationwide events, we also run our own.
This is where you’ll find us this year.
Blog Blog
The IRIS blog is the central location for up and coming products, guest articles and industry insights. Bitesize reading that really packs a punch.
GuidesWebinarsCase StudiesPerspectives Perspectives
Whether you are looking for the latest updates on Workplace Pensions automatic enrolment or news on IFRS, we have a great range of articles to assist.
Coronavirus Help and AdviceSupportKnowledge Base Knowledge Base
At IRIS, we don’t simply deliver on our promise to create powerful management products, we also strive to empower our customers with the knowledge they need to excel.
IRIS Accountancy ProductsIRIS Accountancy SuiteIRIS Accountancy Suite DownloadsWhat’s new in this releaseKnowledge BaseIRIS Upcoming ReleasesIRIS System RequirementsIRIS Help CentreIRIS Training CentreIRIS Accountancy Suite Support CentreIRIS KeytimeIRIS Keytime DownloadsWhat’s new in this releaseIRIS Keytime Knowledge BaseIRIS Upcoming ReleasesIRIS System RequirementsIRIS PTPIRIS PTP DownloadsWhat’s new in this PTP releaseKnowledge BaseIRIS PTP Upcoming ReleasesIRIS PTP System RequirementsIRIS PTP Help CentreIRIS Payroll Products, Bookkeeping & HRIRIS CascadeSupportPayroll SupportPayroll DownloadsKnowledge BaseIRIS P11D SupportIRIS HR Manager SupportIRIS Payroll Professional (Formerly Star Payroll Professional)DownloadsHelp CentreSupport GuideIRIS KashFlowSupportKnowledge BaseAkademy WebinarsOtherDirect Debit MandateIRIS Education SupportIRIS Education SupportIRIS Financials SupportIRIS Education Resource CentreDocument LibrariesPAYE MasterIRIS Payroll BusinessIRIS Bureau PayrollIRIS EarnieIRIS Earnie IQIRIS OpenPayslips & IRIS OpenEnrolIRIS GP PayrollIRIS GP AccountsContact support Contact support
Need help with your IRIS accountancy or payroll solution? Speak to our friendly support team via email or phone.
TrainingPayroll and HR TrainingAccountancy Training Training
Get more out of your existing IRIS software with online or classroom based training.
ShopAboutIRIS Software Group About IRIS Software Group
We exist to simplify the lives of Britain’s businesses by helping create greater operational accuracy and efficiencies in everyday tasks and look forward with confidence.
Contact us Contact us
We are a company built on hiring the best people who are interested in a challenge and want to work with a brand that gets things right for millions of people today and tomorrow.
Locations Locations
IRIS has 16 office locations throughout the UK, including our head office in Langley.
Leaders Leaders
Learn more about IRIS Software Group’s Board and Executive leadership team.
Careers at IRIS Careers at IRIS
We are a company built on hiring the best people who are interested in a challenge and want to work with a brand that gets things right for millions of people today and tomorrow.
News
Cookies
Twitter
LinkedIn
Home / Cookies
Cookies – what are they?
This site uses cookies. Cookies are small text files stored on your computer when you visit certain web pages. They are used remember your preferences and in some cases your purchases from the website. We also use cookies that enable you to more easily share pages you like via social media sites like Facebook and Twitter. They are also used to collect anonymous data about your visit (like which areas of the site you visit and for how long) to help us improve your experience of our site and eliminate errors.Cookies are not unsafe or in themselves a threat to your online privacy as; we don’t store sensitive information such as contact details or payment information, but recent legislation requires that website owners give as much information as possible about cookies used on a website and clear instructions how to refuse them, should you so choose. If you do choose not to allow cookies, please be aware that this site may not be fully functional.For more detailed information about cookies, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.To make this information as clear as possible, as well as listing the cookies we use, we’ve categorised them to help explain what they do.
Cookie Categories and the cookies we use
Strictly necessary cookies
“These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website. Without these cookies services you have asked for, like shopping baskets or e-billing, cannot be provided.”
Please note that we treat usage of our site as acceptance of this type of cookie. While you are free to block them (see below), if you do then we cannot guarantee that this website will be functional.
Cookies from this site:
CookieUsed ByDescriptionExpiry__cf_bmCloudflareThis cookie is used to distinguish between humans and bots. This is beneficial for the website, in order to make valid reports on the use of their website.1 dayBIGipServer#MarketoUsed to distribute traffic to the website on several servers in order to optimise response times.1 daywc_cart_hash_#, wc_fragments_#iris.co.ukNecessary for the operation of the shopping cart functionality. Not installed by other pages on the site.Session
Cookies provided by 3rd parties: None
Performance cookies
The services contained in this section enable IRIS to monitor and analyse web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behaviour.
Google Analytics with anonymised IP (Google Inc.)
Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilises the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualise and personalise the ads of its own advertising network. This integration of Google Analytics anonymises your IP address. It works by shortening your IP address within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be sent to a Google server and shortened within the US.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy – Opt Out. Privacy Shield participant.
ResponseTap (ResponseTap Limited)
ResponseTap is an analytics service provided by ResponseTap Limited.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United Kingdom – Privacy Policy.
Google AdWords conversion tracking (Google Inc.)
Google AdWords conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google Inc. that connects data from the Google AdWords advertising network with actions performed on this Website.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. Privacy Shield participant.
Google Website Optimizer (Google Inc.)
Google Website Optimizer is an A/B testing service provided by Google Inc. Google may use Personal Data to contextualise and personalise the ads of its own advertising network.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. Privacy Shield participant.
Tag Management
This type of service helps the owner to manage the tags or scripts needed on this Website in a centralised fashion.  This results in the users’ data flowing through these services, potentially resulting in the retention of this data.
Google Tag Manager (Google LLC)
Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google LLC.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. Privacy Shield participant.
Functionality cookies
These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. For instance, a website may be able to provide you with local weather reports or traffic news by storing in a cookie the region in which you are currently located. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customise, to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.
Please note that we while you are free to block Performance cookies (see below), if you do then we cannot guarantee that this website will function as expected.
Cookies from this site:
CookieUsed byDescriptioncookieprefwhole siteStores whether the cookie alert bar has been dismissed
Cookies provided by 3rd parties: None
Advertising
Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioural retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behaviour, including those detected outside this Website. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.  In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.
Bing Ads (Microsoft Corporation)
Bing Ads is an advertising service provided by Microsoft Corporation.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy – Opt Out.
Google AdWords (Google Inc.)
Google AdWords conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google Inc. that connects data from the Google AdWords advertising network with actions performed on this Website.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. Privacy Shield participant.
Remarketing and behavioural targeting
This type of service allows this Website and its partners to inform, optimise and serve advertising based on past use of this Website by the User. This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioural targeting activity. In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.
AdRoll (Semantic Sugar, Inc.)
AdRoll is an advertising service provided by Semantic Sugar, Inc.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy – Opt Out.
AdWords Remarketing (Google Inc.)
AdWords Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioural targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the activity of this Website with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy – Opt Out.
Video content
Wistia (Wistia, Inc.)
Wistia is a video content visualization service provided by Wistia, Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. Privacy Shield participant.
YouTube (Google Inc.)
YouTube is a video content service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Website to embed video content on its pages
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage DataPlace of processing: United States – Privacy PolicyPrivacy Shield participant
Social networks and platforms
This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Website. The interaction and information obtained through this Website are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network. This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when you do not use it.
AddThis (Addthis Inc.)
AddThis is a service provided by Clearspring Technologies Inc., which displays a widget that allows interaction with social networks and external platforms as well as sharing the contents of this Website.  Depending on the configuration, this service can display widgets belonging to third parties such as the managers of social networks where interactions are shared. In this case, also the third parties that provide the widget will be informed of interactions and Usage Data on the pages where this service is installed.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.
LinkedIn Website Retargeting (LinkedIn Corporation)
LinkedIn Website Retargeting is a remarketing and behavioural targeting service provided by LinkedIn Corporation that connects the activity of this Website with the LinkedIn advertising network.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy – Opt Out.
Marketo
Marketo
RTP
These cookies are set by Marketo as
part of its Web Personalization and ContentAI Products. They
deliver customized content and features based on user choices, past browsing,
and inferred information.
Session
– 2 years
1st Party
Marketo
Munchkin (_mkto_trk)
This
cookie is set by Marketo. This allows a website to track visitor behavior on
the sites on which the cookie is installed and to link a visitor to the
recipient of an email marketing campaign, to measure campaign effectiveness.
Tracking is performed anonymously until a user identifies himself by
submitting a form.
2
years
1st Party
Twitter Remarketing (Twitter, Inc.)
Twitter Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioural targeting service provided by Twitter, Inc. that connects the activity of this Website with the Twitter advertising network.
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy – Opt Out. Privacy Shield participant.
Owner and Data Controller
IRIS Software Group Limited (470 London Road, Slough, SL3 8QY) Owner contact email: dataprotection@iris.co.uk Since the installation of third-party Cookies and other tracking systems through the services used within this Website cannot be technically controlled by the Owner, any specific references to Cookies and tracking systems installed by third parties are to be considered indicative. In order to obtain complete information, the User is kindly requested to consult the privacy policy for the respective third-party services listed in this document.Given the objective complexity surrounding the identification of technologies based on Cookies, Users are encouraged to contact the Owner should they wish to receive any further information on the use of Cookies by this Website.
Managing Cookies
Please follow the instructions below for your chosen web browser:
Chrome
Click on the ‘Tools’” menu (or the Spanner/Wrench icon) and select ‘Options’.Click the ‘Under the Bonnet’ tab and locate the ‘Privacy’ section, and choose the ‘Content settings’ button.Click the ‘Cookie settings’ tab and choose your preferred settings. The default behaviour is to allow all cookies, but you can fine tune your preferences here, and view the currently set cookies by clicking on ‘All cookies and site data…’
Internet Explorer 9
Click the Tools menu and then Internet Options.Click the Privacy tab.Move the slider to choose your preferred settings. These settings are quite general.For more specific cookie settings click on ‘Advanced’, check the ‘Override cookie handling’ button and modify the settings to suit your requirements. You can also click on ‘Sites’ to set cookie settings for individual websites.
Internet Explorer 6, 7 & 8
Click the Tools menu and then Internet Options.Click the Privacy tab.Move the slider to choose your preferred settings. These settings are quite general.For more specific cookie settings click on Advanced, check the ‘Override cookie handling’ button and modify the settings to suit your requirements.
Firefox 3.5 upwards
Click the Tools menu, then Options.Select the Privacy tab and in the History panel, select “Use custom settings for history”.You can set general cookie preferences using the checkbox, or more specific settings by clicking on ‘Exceptions’. Clicking on ‘Show Cookies’ displays all cookies saved on your computer and also allows you to clear all of them with a single click.
Firefox (pre v 3.5)
Click on Tools, then Options.Select the Privacy tab.Select Cookies. You can then choose your preferred settings.
Apple Safari (v 3 upwards)
Click the Cog icon or Edit on the main menu.Click Preferences, then Security.The ‘Accept cookies’ section allows you to specify your cookie preferences. To remove all cookies, click on ‘Show Cookies’ and ‘Remove All’.
There is also a comprehensive guide on clearing cookies, containing many more browser types, at http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=2
Further information
All about cookies
Cookies on GOV.UK
Your ad choices by Your Online Choices.eu
Please see our privacy policy.
Sign up to our newsletter to receive news on IRIS, our big ideas and latest blog posts.
We use cookies to offer you a better experience, analyse site traffic, and serve targeted advertisements.
By continuing to use this website, you consent to the use of cookies in accordance with our Cookie Policy.
Accept
